Chairman: I give the floor to Jean-Luc Mélenchon for a minute.
JLM: If you really wanted to do something, you would start by forbidding the activities of European banks in tax havens.
You would implement the differential taxation of foreign residents in their country of origin.
But of course you will do nothing of the sort, and you will not implement any measure.
The criminal obstruction of countries that oppose any restricting measures will continue.
The liberalization of capital movements without any tax harmonization will continue.
Tax havens in the EU and in the neighboring countries will continue to be tolerated.
The European regulation of transfer prices that facilitate tax evasion will continue.
And more importantly, these damn austerity policies that destroy tax authorities and customs services that could punish tax evasion will continue.
The directive on the automatic exchanges of tax information - everyone of you can read it - will only allow to take care of the accounts of natural persons,
and not those of companies or hedge funds.
Finally, you keep recommending the development of VAT taxes everywhere.